Eastern Association for Physical Education of College Women (EAPECW) Records, 1910-1995
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- Series VI. COMMITTEE RECORDS, (1920-92); 2.75 linear feet.
  - to Review EAPECW Policies, Committee, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 233)
  - to Review Research Grant Award, Ad-hoc, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 234)
  - Site Selection, 1972-91 (Box 14, Folder 235)
  - Special Committee on Conference Speakers, 1958-59 (Box 14, Folder 236)
  - Special Committee on Criteria for Honorary Membership, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 237)
  - Special Committee on Disposal of 1958 Conference Reports, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 238)
  - Special Committee on Dues, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 239)
  - Special Committee on "New Directions and Interpretations", 1963 (Box 14, Folder 240)
  - Special Committee on Newsletter Editor, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 241)
  - Special Committee on Policy in Regard to Guests and Visitors at EAPECW Conferences, 1961-62 (Box 14, Folder 242)
  - Special Committee on Programs and Annual Reports, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 243)
  - Strategic Action Committee, 1991-92 (Box 14, Folder 244)
  - Structure and Function, 1976-78 (Box 14, Folder 245)
  - Test Committee
    - Correspondence, 1932-37 (Box 14, Folder 246)
    - Tests and Results, 1932-37 (Box 14, Folder 247)
- Series VII. PROGRAMS
  - Professional seminars/Spectrum Consultants, 1983-86 (Box 15, Folder 248)
  - Margaret Paulding Lecture Series establishment, 1993-95 (Box 15, Folder 249)
  - Margaret Paulding Lecture text by Carole Oglesby, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 250)
- Series VIII. MEETINGS AND CONFERENCES
  - Annual Business Meeting
    - Agendas, 1975-91 (Box 16, Folder 251)
    - Minutes, 1939-92 (Box 16, Folder 252)
  - General
    - circa 1910-40 (Box 16, Folder 253-279)
    - 1941-58 (Box 17, Folder 280-298)
    - 1959-66 (Box 18, Folder 299-310)
    - 1967-77 (Box 19, Folder 311-321)
    - 1978-87 (Box 20, Folder 322-331)
    - 1988-92 (Box 21, Folder 332-337)
  - Conference Tapes (reel-to-reel and cassette)
    - 1958
      - Ethel Alpenfels, "The Role of Values in a Changing American Scene" (3 tapes), 1958 (Box 22)
      - Eleanor Metheny, "The Intricate Web," 10/24, and group discussion, 10/25 (Box 22)
    - 1959
      - Bertha Adkins, "Government Resources and Services--Their Importance in Service in Higher Education for Women," 10/23, Celeste Ulrich "The Cast Shadow", and discussion period (Box 22)
      - Discussion period, 10/23 p.m. (Box 22)
      - Panel: Elizabeth Beall, Celeste Ulrich, Edith Cobane, Jean Berger, Patty Smyth, 10/24 (Box 22)
      - Minnie Lynn, "The Role of Our Professional Organization in the Next Decade, 10/24 (Box 22)
    - 1960
      - Edward Steitz, "The Application of Scientific Principles in Teaching Physical Education and Athletic Skills" 10/22 (Box 23)
      - Janet Wessell, "SOS--State of Shape" 10/21 (Box 23)
      - Charles C. Noble, "Youth Has a Word For It" 10/22 (Box 23)
      - Arthur Steinhaus, "What I Have Learned From Animals" 10/20 (Box 23)
    - 50th Anniversary, 10/16/1965 (Box 23)
    - Meetings,10/27-28, 1967 (Box 23)
    - Betty Spears, "Remembering EAPECW,"6/9, 1990 (Box 23)
- Series IX. AFFILIATIONS
  - General, 1985-87 (Box 24, Folder 338)
  - American Association for Health, Physical Education, and Recreation (AAHPER), Division for Girls' and Women's Sports (DGWS), 1958-80 (Box 24, Folder 339)
  - AAHPER, National Research Committee, 1939-71 (Box 24, Folder 340)
  - American Physical Education Association (APEA), National Section for Girls' and Women's Sports (NSGWS), 1935, undated (Box 24, Folder 341)
  - Athletic and Recreation Federation of College Women (ARFCW), 1958 (Box 24, Folder 342)
  - Eastern Association of Intercollegiate Athletics for Women (EAIAW), 1971-78 (Box 24, Folder 343)
  - Eastern Commission for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women (ECIAW), 1972 (Box 24, Folder 344)
  - National Association for Physical Education of College Women (NAPECW) and regional APECWs, 1917-75, undated (Box 24, Folder 345)
  - NAPECW, reports to, 1940-78 (Box 24, Folder 346)
  - National Association for Physical Education in Higher Education (NAPEHE), 1980-90 (Box 24, Folder 347)
- Series X. PUBLICATIONS
  - Brochures, 1982/83-1989/90 (Box 24, Folder 348)
  - Business Report/Business Newsletter, 1960-69 (Box 24, Folder 349-350)
  - Newsletters, 1936-61 (Box 24, Folder 351-352)
  - Newsletters, 1962-91 (Box 25, Folder 353-357)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - EAPECW Merit Award recipients: matted color photographs by Jean K. Marsh (incomplete), 1970-90 (Box 26)